William S. Rosecrans Papers
William S. Rosecrans Papers,
- Papers
  - Papers of the Rosecrans Family
    - Miscellaneous clippings. (Box 103)
    - Memorabilia and clippings of William S. Rosecrans. (Box 104)
    - Writings of William S. Rosecrans, including biographical material. (Box 105)
    - Writings and memorabilia of Adrian L. and Ann D. Rosecrans. (Box 106)
    - Writings and memorabilia of Carl F., Mary L., and Sylvester H. Rosecrans, and including some memorabilia of the Hegeman family. (Box 107)
    - Family photographs. (Box 108-110)
    - Certificates, diplomas, commissions, etc., 1842-1898. (Box 124)
- [Miscellaneous]
  - “Regalia.” (Box 111)
    Shoulder epaulets, cross, medals, harness trappings, etc.
  - Family papers. (Boxes 112-116)
  - Book of clippings. (Box 118)
    Also, photograph of W.S. Rosecrans.
    (Formerly package 5)
  - Photographs of General & Mrs. Rosecrans. (Box 119)
    (Formerly package 4)
  - Original wrappers from his papers. (Boxes 120-121)
    (Formerly package 3)
  - 2 fore and aft hats. (Box 122)
  - 2 flags. (Box 123)
  - Walking stick. (Box 125)
  - Printed material. (Box 126)
  - Photograph of General Rosecrans, ca. 1880s., (Framed) (Box 118)
  - Leather belt.
    (Added July 1969)
    Missing
  - Writings by Carl Frederick Rosecrans., (3 folders, ca. 150 pieces) (Box 107)
  - Ledger of clippings re the death of President Garfield, 1881, and the Spanish-American War, 1898, especially the naval battles and Admiral Dewey., (1 scrapbook)
  - Original oil portrait of General Rosecrans, by George P.A. Healy.
  - Original oil portrait of Anne Eliza Hegeman Rosecrans.
  - Fire screen with original glass from the Rosecrans home in San Rafael, California.
  - Wooden cane carved by a soldier in General Rosecrans' army.
  - 2 swords.
  - Silver tea service and other items (separate list on file).
  - 2 epaulet pins.
  - Etching of General Rosecrans., (Framed)
  - Original oil portrait of Adjutant General John McManman. By William Morris, 1871., (In gold frame)
  - Oil portrait of Carmelita (Rosecrans) Ewing. By Lucia Warren, 1950.
  - Photographs. (Box 119)
    2 photographs of the Healy paintings of General Rosecrans and Mrs. Rosecrans (Both framed).
    1 photograph of a woman - unidentified.
    1 unframed photograph of the general.
  - General History of Orange County., (Photostats, pp.26-27 and 52) (Box 13)
    re Storm King Mountains, Crow-Nest, Benny's and Stony Lonesome.
  - United States Military Academy, West Point (Box 13)
    - Post order book (no.1), February 19, 1838-June 3, 1842. (Box 13)
      Orders re W.S. Rosecrans.
    - Orders (no.37, part 6). (Box 13)
      Promoted Corporal.
    - Special Order (no.60). West Point, June 10, 1840., (p.207) (Box 13)
      Rosecrans detailed to instruct candidates for admission.
    - Orders (no.35) June 22, 1840., (p.210) (Box 13)
      Rosecrans Quarter Master Sargeant.
    - Orders (no.26) June 21, 1841., (p.263) (Box 13)
    - Special Order (no.68) August 31, 1841., (p.278) (Box 13)
      Rosecrans Assistant Professor in Mathematics.
    - Special Order (no.127) December 14, 1841., (p.300) (Box 13)
      Rosecrans report to Professor Albert E. Church for orders.
    - Orders (no.66, Part 2) December 30, 1841., (p.301) (Box 13)
      Rosecrans appointed to act as Assistant Professor of Mathematics with all considerations attached thereto until further orders.
    - Special Order (no.10) January 23, 1842., (p.310) (Box 13)
      Rosecrans relieved from duty as Assistant Professor and will report to Commandant of Cadets for orders.
  - Rosecrans Property, Horton addition, San Diego. (Box 13)
    Five Plats, Lots 70- 346- 369- 372- 206- 205- 211.
    (Courtesy James D. Forward, Jr. Vice President, Title Insurance and Trust Company, San Diego)
  - History of Guns - One that fired first shot and one that fired the last shot of the Civil War., (pp.55, 57) (Box 13)
    (From Catalogue of the U.S. Military Academy Museum. West Point, 1944)
  - West Point Coat of Arms, History of. (Box 13)
  - Regulations, U.S. Military Academy, 1839., (pp.31-34) (Box 13)
    Natural and Experimental Philosophy (p.31).
    Chemistry and Mineralogy (p.32).
    Artillery (p.33).
    Engineering and the Science of War (p.34).
  - Synopsis of Courses of Studies at U.S. Military Academy and Instructors, 1845-1847. (Box 13)
  - Reserved for future use. (Box 13)
- Original oil portrait of Ann Eliza (Hegeman) Rosecrans, by George P.A. Healy, 1862., Catalogued: ORIG 99. Added to the Rosecrans collection at the bequest of Carmelita (Rosecrans) Ewing, March, 1969.
- Original oil portrait of unidentified Rosecrans, 1891., In gold frame.; Added to the Rosecrans collection at the bequest of Carmelita (Rosecrans) Ewing, March, 1969.
- Oil portrait of Carmelita (Rosecrans) Ewing, by Lucia Warren, 1950., Added to the Rosecrans collection at the bequest of Carmelita (Rosecrans) Ewing, March, 1969.
- Photographs
  - 2 photographs of the Healy paintings of General Rosecrans and Mrs. Rosecrans., Both framed. (Box 119)
  - 1 photograph of a woman - unidentified. (Box 119)
  - 1 unframed photograph of the general. (Box 119)
  - Framed photograph of General Rosecrans, ca. 1880s. (Box 118)
- Objects
  - 2 sets of shoulder pieces - bars and epaulets.
  - 2 sabers, Wrapped in a package.
  - 2 horse harnesses (Box 111)
  - 1 wooden cross (Box 111)
  - 1 certificate for 1500 shares of stock in a gold mining company, 1890.
- 1 leather belt., Added July, 1969.
- Writings by Carl Frederick Rosecrans., 3 folders (ca. 150 pieces); Added July, 1969. (Box 107)
- Ledger of clippings, 1 scrapbook.; Added July, 1969. (Box 118)
  Re: the death of President Garfield, 1881, and the Spanish-American War, 1898, especially the naval battles and Admiral Dewey.
- Original oil portrait of General Rosecrans, by George P.A. Healy., Added January, 1982.
- Original oil portrait of Anne Eliza Hegeman Rosecrans., Added January, 1982.
- Fire screen with original glass from the Rosecrans home in San Rafael, California., Added January, 1982.
- Wooden cane carved by a soldier in General Rosecrans' army., Added January, 1982.
- 2 swords, Added January, 1982.
- 2 epaulet pins, Added January, 1982.
- Silver tea service and other items, (separate list on file) Added January, 1982.
- Framed etching of General Rosecrans, Added January, 1982.
A Partial Index of Correspondents, Manuscripts, and Subjects in the Rosecrans Papers
A Note on the use of the Index
References in the index are to boxes and to folders or items within a single box.
The location and approximate chronological sequence of the items indexed can be obtained from the Conspectus in the previous section.
Passim means there are scattered references in the box or folder.
Albert, John J. (Letter from) Box 6, folder 97
Abolition of slavery: Box 2, folder 72
Adams, Charles Francis (1807-1886) (Letter from) Box 33, folder 61A
Adams, Charles Francis (1807-1886)(Letter to) Box 52, folder 1
Adams, Daniel W. (Letter from) Box 20, folder 51
Adams, John Quincy (Mention of) Box 1, folder 48
Alden, James (1810-1877) (Letter from) Box 20, folder 48
Alden, James (1810-1877) (Letter to) Box 50, folder 3
Alemany, José S. (Letters from) Box 20, folder 99
Box 22, folder 82
Box 23, folder 54
Box 27, folder 76
Box 30, folder 26
Box 34, folders 11,95,110,124
Box 41, folder 110
Box 54, folder 48
Box 69, folder 101
Box 70, folder 3
Alemany, José S. (Letters to) Box 50, folder 1
Box 51, folder 2
Box 52, folder 1
Alexander, Barton S. (Letters from) Box 2, folders 1, 62, 65, 88, 130, 159, 164
Box 3, folder 97
Alexander, Barton S. (Mention of) Box 11, folder 37
Box 35, folder 3
Box 59, folder 3
Box 60, folder 59
Allen, Robert (1812-1886)(Letters to) Box 44, folder 40
Box 45, folders 27, 51, 54
Box 46, folder 20
Altamirano, Ignacio M. (Letter from) Box 22, folder 98
Amelia Island, Nassau County, Florida (Fortifications at) Box 1, folders 10, 29
American & Mexican Company, New York Box 12, folders 116-117
American Knights, Order of the Box 10, folders 21-24
Box 48, folders 135
American Knights, Order of the American (“Know-Nothing”) Party Box 5, folder 134A
Box 66, folder 55
Ames, Oakes (Letter from) Box 12, folder 88
Ames, Oakes (Letter to) Box 49, folders 5-6
Ames, Oakes (Mention of) Box 12, folder 78
Box 16, folder 159
Andrew, John A. (Letter from) Box 8, folders 104, 111
Andrew, John A. (Letter to) Box 45, folder 119
Andrews, Ebenezer B. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 157
Armstrong, John (1775-1843) (Mention of) Box 78, folder 89
Army and Navy Club, New York Box 21, folder 36
Arnold, Isaac N. (Letter from) Box 53, folder 103
Asboth, Alexander S. (Mention of) Box 59, folder 37
Aspinwall, William H. (Letter from) Box 17, folder 146
Aspinwall, William H.(Letter to) Box 49, folder 6
Aspinwall, William H. (Mention of) Box 61, folder 17
Astor, John Jacob (1822-1890) (Letter from) Box 16, folders 13, 57, 138, 145
Astor, John Jacob (1822-1890)(Letter to) Box 49, folder 6 (2 letters)
Astor, John Jacob (1822-1890) (Mention of) Box 61, folders 17-18
Box 68, folder 6
Atchison, Topeka & Santa Fe Railroad Company Box 34, folder 102
Box 35, folder 53
Box 36, folder 5
Box 37, folders 26, 58
Box 39, folder 9
Atlantic & Great Western Railroad Company Box 68, folders 41-42
Atlantic & Pacific Railroad Company Box 21, folder 8
Box 68, folder 5
Axtell, Samuel B. (Letter from) Box 16, folder 85
Axtell, Samuel B.(Letters to) Box 50, folders 1 (2 letters), 2 (2 letters)
Axtell, Samuel B. (Mention of) Box 14, folder 47
Ayres, Romeyn B. (Letter from) Box 3, folder 8
Ayres, Romeyn B. (Manuscript by) Box 80, folder 7
Bache, Alexander D. (Letters from) Box 3, folders 48, 55
Box 8, folder 37
Box 9, folder 57
Bailey, Jacob W. (Letters from) Box 6, folder 36
Box 69, folder 8
Baird, Spencer F.(Letters to) Box 52, folder 3 (2 letters)
Baker, Conrad (Letter from) Box 16, folder 153
Balcárcel, Blas (Letters from) Box 14, folder 99
Box 16, folders 6, 33
Box 17, folder 24
Box 18, folder 37
Box 19, folders 31, 100
Box 20, folder 49
Box 23, folders 6, 9, 13
Box 24, folder 107
Box 26, folders 40, 73, 76, 117, 123-124, 126, 128-129, 139-141, 144, 154
Box 90, folders 22-24, 26, 31
Balcárcel, Blas (Letters to) Box 47, folders 89, 139-138
Box 48, folders 1-8, 13-14
Box 49, folder 6 (4 letters)
Box 50, folders 1 (3 letters), 2 (2 letters), 3
Box 51, folders 1 (6 letters), 2 (8 letters), 3
Box 54, folder 54
Box 90, folders 25, 30
Balcárcel, Blas (Mention of) Box 14, folder 94A
Box 26, folders 105, 156
Box 27, folder 131
Bancroft, Hubert Howe (Letter to) Box 48, folder 125
Bangs, Francis N. (Letter to) Box 52, folder 3
Bank of the U.S., 1816-1836 (Bill to charter, 1814) Box 78, folder 99
Banks, Nathaniel P. (Letters from) Box 9, folder 131
Box 17, folder 11
Banks, Nathaniel P.(Letters to) Box 47, folder 71
Box 49, folder 6 (2 letters)
Banks, Nathaniel P. (Mention of) Box 59, folder 30
Box 61, folder 20
Box 68, folder 11
Banning, Phineas (Mention of) Box 12, folder 16
Box 60, folder 41
Barker, Jacob (Mention of) Box 78, folder 90
Barnett, James (1821-1911) (Letters from) Box 18, folder 74
Box 19, folder 87
Barnum, William H. (Letter from) Box 38, folder 84
Bartlett, William H.C. (Letters from) Box 1, folder 23
Box 2, folder 36
Box 3, folder 137
Bates, Joshua H. (b. ca. 1817) (Letter from) Box 9, folder 67
Beatty, John (1828-1914) (Letter to) Box 50, folder 2
Beauregard, Pierre G.T. (Letters from) Box 12, folders 32, 70
Box 26, folder 112
Beauregard, Pierre G.T. (Mention of) Box 2, folder 157
Box 27, folder 55
Box 66, folder 110
Box 78, folder 56
Beecher, Henry Ward (Letter to) Box 50, folder 1
Belknap, William W. (Mention of) Box 21, folder 10
Bell, William A. (Letters from) Box 22, folders 1, 4, 48
Bell, William A. (Mention of) Box 22, folders 45, 91
Bellows, Henry W. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 13
Belmont, August (Mention of) Box 14, folder 18
Belton, Francis S. (Letters from) Box 2, folders 56A, 98
Box 3, folder 40
Box 4, folders 20, 50
Belton, Francis S. (Mention of) Box 2, folders 54-55
Box 3, folders 59, 100
Benham, Henry W. (Letters from) Box 2, folder 128
Box 3, folders 9, 28-29, 33, 127
Box 4, folder 5
Box 7, folder 41
Box 53, folder 59
Benham, Henry W. (Mention of) Box 43, folder 133
Box 59, folders 10, 12, 24, 27, 32, 50
Box 66, folder 108
Benicia, California Box 4, folder 98B
Benjamin, Calvin (Letters from) Box 1, folders 42, 49, 66, 84
Bennett, James G. (Letter of) Box 30, folder 69
Bennett, James G. (Mention of) Box 62, folder 5
Benton, James G. (Letters from) Box 1, folders 37, 43, 46, 55, 58, 65, 92
Box 7, folder 29
Box 35, folders 3, 29, 55
Box 36, folders 4, 24
Benton, James G. (Mention of) Box 6, folder 148
Benton, Thomas H. (Mention of) Box 40, folder 22
Berry, Campbell P. (Printed speeches by) Box 87, folders 23, 25
Bidwell, John (Letter from) Box 42, folder 79
Big Sewall Mountain, West Virginia (Evacuation of) Box 7, folder 145
Billings, Frederick (Letter from) Box 35, folder 114
Black, Jeremiah S. (Mention of) Box 61, folder 21
Blaine, James G. (Letters from) Box 42, folders 44, 93
Blaine, James G. (Mention of) Box 43, folders 1-5
Box 62, folder 65
Blair, Austin (Letters to) Box 45, folders 45, 77
Blair, Francis P.(Letter to) Box 49, folder 2
Blair, Montgomery (Recollections by) Box 81, folder 19
Blenker, Louis (Letter from) Box 8, folder 9
Blenker, Louis (Mention of) Box 59, folders 30-31, 35
Blue & Gray Hancock Central Legion, San Francisco Boxes 38-39
Blunt, James G. (Letter from) Box 7, folder 154
Blow, Henry T. (Letter from) Box 10, folder 22
Boarman, Charles (Mention of) Box 2, folder 158
Bond, Frank S. (Letters from) Box 31, folders 15, 50
Box 117, folders 7, 29
Box 32, folder 62
Box 33, folders 94, 130-131
Box 34, folders 89, 93, 102
Box 36, folder 68
Box 54, folder 37
Box 69, folder 48
Box 78, folder 68
Bond, Frank S. (Letters to) Box 49, folder 5 (3 letters)
Bond, Frank S. (Mention of) Box 9, folders 116, 135
Boutwell, Charles L. (Letter to) Box 53, folder 113
Bowen, Thomas M. (Letter from) Box 9, folder 146
Bowles, Samuel (Letter to) Box 49, folder 6
Bowman, Alexander H. (Letter from) Box 3, folder 114
Boyd, Sempronius H. (Letters from) Box 9, folder 102
Box 10, folder 20
Bragg, Braxton (Mention of) Box 1, folder 52
Box 8, folders 94, 96, 103B, 118, 127
Box 59, folders 45, 89, 91
Box 66, folder 111
Box 82, folder 11
Brannan, John M. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 66
Breck, Samuel (Letter from) Box 10, folder 42
Brewster, Henry (Letter from) Box 2, folder 54B
Brinkerhoff, Jacob (Letter from) Box 8, folder 160
Broadhead, James O.(Letter to) Box 52, folder 3
Brown, Benjamin Gratz (Letters from) Box 9, folder 145
Box 11, folder 18
Brown, Benjamin Gratz (Letter to) Box 49, folder 2
Brown, Harvey (1795-1874) (Mention of) Box 2, folder 50A
Browne, John Ross (Letter from) Box 20, folder 3
Brownson, Orestes A. (Letter to) Box 46, folder 84
Brownson, Orestes A. (Mention of) Box 66, folder 52
Brunton, David W. (Letter from) Box 31, folder 124
Buchanan, Robert C. (Letters from) Box 4, folders 95, 97
Box 5, folders 110, 143
Buchanan, Robert C.(Letters to) Box 49, folder 1
Buckalew, Charles R. (Mention of) Box 24, folder 62
Buell, Don Carlos (Letter to) Box 53, folder 53
Buell, Don Carlos (Mention of) Box 7, folders 13, 135
Box 59, folders 37, 39, 46, 50, 53, 61
Bundy, Jonas M. (Letters from) Box 21, folder 7
Box 51, folder 2
Bundy, Jonas M. (Mention of) Box 48, folder 62
Burlingame, Anson (Letter from) Box 11, folder 23
Burlingame, Anson (Mention of) Box 60, folder 38
Box 71, folder 20
Box 77, folder 54
Burlingame, Edward L. (Letters from) Box 11, folder 23A
Box 117, folder 44
Box 77, folders 68-69
Burlingame, Edward L. (Mention of) Box 63, folder 24
Box 71, folders 102-103
Burnett, Ward B. (Letter from) Box 12, folder 97
Burnett, Ward B. (Mention of) Box 3, folder 89
Burns, William W. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 25
Burnside, Ambrose E. (Letters from) Box 8, folders 57, 90, 123-124, 131, 134, 136-137
Box 14, folder 20
Box 53, folders 70, 76-77
Box 69, folder 17
Burnside, Ambrose E.(Letters to) Box 45, folder 137
Box 46, folders 2-3, 24
Burnside, Ambrose E. (Mention of) Box 3, folder 59
Box 8, folders 89, 109, 117, 119-120, 125, 135, 140
Box 9, folder 20
Box 31, folder 72
Butler, Benjamin F. (1818-1893) (Mention of) Box 11, folder 64
Box 21, folder 3
Box 61, folder 68A
Box 67, folder 60
Butterfield, Daniel (Letter from) Box 14, folder 17A
Butterfield, Daniel (Letter of) Box 80, folder 25
Cagwin's (Francis L.) Spader Plow Box 50, folder 3
Box 51, folder 3
Box 99, folder 1
Calhoun, John C. (Mention of) Box 78, folders 89, 92
California & Texas Railroad Company Box 23, folder 87
California & Texas Railway Construction Company, Philadelphia Box 31, folder 90
Box 32, folder 94
California, Atlantic & Pacific Railroad Company Box 24, folder 37
California Gold Rush Box 78, folders 116-120
California, Lower scheme of U.S. citizens to purchase from Mexico: Box 61, folder 68A
California Pacific Railroad Company Box 96, folder 10
California Southern Coast Railroad Company Box 16, folders 50, 133, 142, 151-152, 160
Box 17, folders 14, 18, 20, 85, 91, 113, 125, 138, 151, 168
Box 19, folders 30, 51-58, 60, 63, 154, 156
Box 20, folders 43, 67
Box 21, folders 17, 22
Box 47, folders 81-82, 86
Box 50, folder 1
Box 53, folders 122-124
Box 55, folder 109
Box 61, folders 19, 25-26, 28-31, 33, 44, 47, 49
Box 68, folder 8
Box 74, folder 60
Box 96, folders 6, 11
Calistoga, California (Description of geysers near) Box 74, folder 12
Calkins, William H. (Printed speech by) Box 87, folder 21
Calvert, George Henry (Letter from) Box 3, folder 150
Cameron, Simon (Document signed by) Box 124, folder 6
Cameron, Simon (Letters from) Box 80, folder 9
Box 90, folder 9
Cameron, Simon (Letters to) Box 44, folder 21
Box 49, folder 6
Box 53, folder 19
Cameron, Simon (Mention of) Box 14, folder 49
Camp Chase, Columbus, Ohio (Organization of in 1861) Box 7, folder 31
Camp Dennison, Cincinnati (Water supply for in 1861) Box 7, folder 33
Campbell, Lewis Davis (Letter from) Box 12, folder 10
Canby, Edward R.S. (Letter from) Box 10, folder 39
Canby, Edward R.S.(Letters to) Box 49, folder 2 (5 letters)
Box 53, folders 93-94, 96
Canby, Edward R.S. (Mention of) Box 9, folders 143, 153, 154
Box 10, folders 92, 112, 119
Cannel Coal Company, Coal River, West Virginia Box 5, folders 94, 106, 141, 147
Box 6, folders 8, 81, 86, 113, 115, 118, 122, 124, 131, 140, 149
Box 7, folder 2
Box 58, folder 90
Capen, Nahum (Letters from) Box 18, folders 7, 31
Carbon River Coal Mining Company, San Francisco Box 35
Box 36, folders 29, 38-39, 51
Box 37, folder 29
Carey, Henry C. (Letter from) Box 19, folder 151
Carlin, William P. (Letter from) Box 9, folder 87
Carnifex Ferry, West Virginia, Battle of Box 36, folder 56
Box 59, folder 16
Box 66, folder 108
Carpenter, Matthew H. (Letters from) Box 16, folders 91, 117-118, 121, 134, 168
Box 17, folder 4
Carpenter, Matthew H. (Letters to) Box 50, folder 1
Box 51, folders 1, 3
Cass, Lewis (Letters to) Box 53, folder 6
Cass, Lewis (Mention of) Box 53, folder 140
Box 66, folder 39
Casserly, Eugene (Letters from) Box 14, folder 131
Box 16, folder 97
Box 38, folder 79
Casserly, Eugene (Letter to) Box 53, folder 112
Casserly, Eugene (Mention of) Box 14, folders 26, 32
Box 24, folder 80
Box 61, folder 2
Church in Mexico Box 14, folder 20A
Box 30, folder 69
Catholicism in the U.S. Army Boxes 1-4, passim
Box 6, folder 2
Ceballos, José (Suppression of revolt of 1869 in Merida, Yucatan) Box 11, folder 64
Centinela Land Company, Los Angeles Box 29, folders 98, 108
Box 30, folders 2, 31, 36
Central Pacific Railroad Company Box 12, folder 128
Box 15, folder 25
Box 21, folders 17, 22, 51
Box 27, folder 170
Box 33, folder 112
Box 68, folder 5
Chamberlain, Joshua L.(Letters to) Box 50, folders 1, 2
Chandler, John (1762-1841) (Mention of) Box 78, folder 87
Chandler, Zachariah (Mention of) Box 19, folder 32
Chase, Salmon P. (Letters from) Box 7, folders 62, 135, 153
Box 8, folders 4, 52
Box 15, folder 22
Box 16, folder 87
Box 18, folder 105
Chase, Salmon P.(Letters to) Box 47, folders 26, 60, 85
Box 49, folders 2, 6 (4 letters)
Chase, Salmon P. (Mention of) Box 2, folder 110
Box 9, folder 104
Box 10, folder 156
Box 12, folder 37
Box 14, folder 54
Box 37, folder 12
Box 38, folder 136
Box 47, folder 64
Box 59, folder 3
Box 61, folder 23
Chattanooga, Tennessee (Battle of, 1863) Box 10, folder 4
Chattanooga, Tennessee (Fortifications at) Box 9, folder 20
Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad Company Box 22, folder 69
Chetlain, August L.(Letters to) Box 44, folders 50-53, 84-85, 102, 104
Chickamauga, Battle of, 1863 Box 8, folders 121-130, 132, 154
Box 9, folders 13, 36-37, 40, 57, 62, 72, 86, 109
Box 10, folders 4, 165
Box 30, folder 58
Box 31, folders 41-42
Box 35, folders 37, 87, 99
Box 42, folder 147
Box 43, folders 1-40, passim, 76, 79
Box 46
Box 47, folder 77
Box 48, folders 18, 36-37, 61-63, 66, 74, 117-118, 136, 143
Box 53, folders 72-77
Box 54, folder 49
Box 59, folder 94
Box 66, folder 113
Box 73, folder 31
Box 80, folder 35
Box 82, folders 19, 21
Box 86, folder 4
Chinese Exclusion Box 62, folders 118-119, 121
Box 63, folder 112
Box 87, folders 21-24
Box 88, folder 9
Chinese in the U.S. Box 20, folders 70, 98
Box 21, folders 18, 145
Box 38, folder 135
Box 39, folder 101
Box 40, folders 20-21, 44, 77
Church, William C. (Letter from) Box 9, folder 29
Church, William C.(Letter to) Box 49, folder 6
Cincinnati, Ohio (Great Western Sanitary Fair at, 1863) Box 9, folders 23-24, 43, 46, 75
Cincinnati Southern Railroad Box 20, folder 19
Cist, Henry M. (Letter from) Box 11, folder 55
Cist, Henry M. (Letter to) Box 47, folder 44
Box 51, folder 4
Box 81, folder 20
Civil Service Reform (Rosecrans' views on) Box 48, folder 115
Clay, Henry (Mention of) Box 1, folder 47
Clem, John L. (Letter from) Box 40, folder 33
Clemens, Samuel L. (Mention of) Box 11, folder 118
Clements, Courtland C. (Letters from) Box 28, folder 16
Cleveland, Grover (Documents signed by) Box 124, folder 18 (2 documents)
Cleveland, Grover (Letter to) Box 54, folder 82
Clinton, DeWitt (Mention of) Box 78, folder 87
Cluseret, Gustave P. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 161
Coal oil (Refining of) Box 6
Box 9, folder 71
Coal River Navigation Company, West Virginia Box 6, folders 66, 82, 88, 92, 96, 112, 121, 125, 136, 138
Coburn, John (Letters from) Box 30, folders 41, 60, 101
Box 31, folder 17
Cole, Cornelius (Mention of) Box 12, folder 60
Box 14, folderss 26, 47
Box 21, folder 132
Box 24, folder 80
Box 26, folder 67
Colorado - Subscriptions to the Mexican Interoceanic Railroad: Box 26, folder 61
Colorado City Company Box 20, folder 106
Box 21, folder 44
Committee on the Conduct of the War Box 10, folders 139, 155, 169-170
Box 11, folder 15
Box 60, folders 5-6
Box 71, folder 7
Box 78, folder 80
Box 81, folders 10, 10A
Compañia Mexicana Box 30, folders 121, 124
Box 31, folder 20A
Box 117, folders 34, 46, 120
Box 32, folders 86, 103
Box 93, folders 29-30
Conkling, Roscoe (Mention of) Box 14, folder 49
Conness, John(Letters to) Box 49, folder 5
Conness, John (Mention of) Box 10, folder 22
Box 14, folder 47
Conrad, Charles M. (Mention of) Box 2, folder 155
Consolidated Tobacco Company, Gilroy, California Box 28
Box 48, folder 16
Box 99, folders 2-4
Cooke, Henry D. Box 49, folder 6
Cooke, Jay(Letters to) Box 49, folder 6 (2 letters)
Cooke, Jay (Mention of) Box 16, folder 116
Box 61, folder 23
Cooper, Samuel (1798-1876) (Letters from) Box 3, folders 121, 128
Box 5, folder 57
Cooper, Samuel (1798-1876) (Letter to) Box 2, folder 82
Corbin, Henry C. (Letter from) Box 36, folder 58
Corcoran, William W. (Letter to) Box 52, folder 3
Corinth, Battle of, 1862 Box 6, folder 68
Box 7, folder 133, passim
Box 7, folder 136
Box 11, folder 127
Box 34, folder 100
Box 40, folder 113
Box 44, folders 40-141
Box 56, folder 35
Box 59, folders 57-59
Box 62, folder 35
Box 64, folder 72
Box 81, folder 23
Box 82, folders 17-18, 22
Corinth, Battle of, 1862 (Occupation of) Box 59, folder 39
Corona, Ramon (Letters from) Box 19, folder 45
Box 22, folder 95